### **Tham Yik Foong**

Location: Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia | Current Location: Nottingham, United Kingdom

Telephone: +44 7541 332875 | Email: Tham yikfoong@outlook.com

**Profile Summary** 

A current Master's degree student studying the field of Machine Learning in Science at University of Nottingham. Current research interests lie in *Reinforcement Learning, Intelligent Agent System* and *Spiking Neural Network*. Previously a software engineer from ATTD department, Intel; delivering products such as station controller and have acquired knowledge of product manufacturing, software architecture design, and communication skill. Committed to professional development and continuous learning in the field of artificial intelligent, while also having a genuine interest in artificial general intelligence.

#### Education

MSc Machine learning in science

University of Nottingham (2019 - present)

**BSc (Hons)** Bachelor of Software Engineering with Multimedia

Limkokwing University (2015 – 2017)

CGPA: 3.9/4.0 (First Class)

### **Career Summary**

# Mar 2018 – July 2019 Software Engineer (ATTD Department) Intel

#### Outline

Develop station controller (machine controller) that communicates with equipment and backend system, controlling the business flow of product manufacturing. This position required knowledge of object-oriented programming and design pattern, understanding the business process of product manufacturing, communication skill as this position work closely with individuals from different factory sites across different countries.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Develop station controller in C# and gather requirements from tech lead and customer (module integrator)
- Testing station controller to ensure it run smoothly in production environment
- Provide code level technical support

 Assigned to compose a station controller development guide and provide couching for peer and new hire

## July 2018 – Sept 2019 (6 Sessions) Tutor MY EDVENTURE

#### Outline

As a tutor of MyEdventure coding bootcamp, teaching subject include HTML, CSS, Javascript.

#### Key Responsibilities

- Prepare teaching material
- Teaching and provide guidance

# Jun 2018 – Sept 2019 Web Developer Intern TIME.COM

#### Outline

Design and develop webpages for one of the major ISP in Malaysia.

#### Key Responsibilities

 Design and develop webpages, company internal web tool, online survey form using HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP

#### Additional Skill

#### Language:

- English (IELTS overall marking: 7.0)
- Bahasa Malay
- Cantonese
- Chinese

### Software:

- Sony Vegas (Video Editing Software)
- Unity (Simulation and Game Engine)
- Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint
- Adobe Photoshop
- AutoCAD

#### Programming Language:

- Javascript (intermediate)
- HTML / CSS (Advanced)
- Java (intermediate)
- PHP (intermediate)
- C++ (intermediate)
- Python (Advanced)
- C# (Advanced)

Any transcripts, additional documents and references are available on request.